Milan

The city of Rome has a violent foundation legend, one that mirrors much of the political and military infighting that happens between the great families of Rome. Romulus murdered Remus for jumping over the walls of the city, and then named himself King and renamed the city in his own honour. The patrician families of Rome claim descent from the adventurers, exiles and warriors Romulus recruited to help establish his city. The Scipii should be numbered among these ancient bloodlines. 

They are not, perhaps, of quite the first rank, although this in itself means that they are keen to prove themselves the equal of any other Romans, but they are certainly among the optimates, the aristocracy of the city, and have been for many generations. They are important people, used to the privileges of rank and the usages of power, both to further Rome’s ambitions and that of their own family. They have also produced able politicians and generals – the two go hand-in-hand in Rome, as political success rarely comes without success on the battlefield. 

They are, however, unusual in a couple of respects for a Roman family of the old ways. Firstly, they are extravagantly wealthy. Wealth is one thing, and this always brings power with it, but their use of wealth has sometimes surprised more conservative Romans (and Romans are nothing if not conservative). The Scipii also have a taste for Greek learning and culture, again something that surprises and concerns the conservative elements. Nevertheless, despite these un-Roman ways, the Scipii have the political skills and military competence to make their family greatest in Rome, and possibly the rulers of the known world. They may only directly control a couple of provinces in Italy and Sicily, but their ambitions are boundless... and realistic.
